Welcome, this is an extremely
important video for all those who are
aspiring copywriters. I decided to make a very
rich, extremely brief
summary of the basics of
copywriting, so how to write
copy, what you understand best, how
this world works, what it is about,
so let's take 30 seconds or a
minute to define what copywriting is,
copywriting plus writing is simply the
writing of copies, copywriting not to be
confused with copyright, the
YouTube copyright has
nothing to do with it, what is copywriting, so it's about
writing copies, but what is
this copy? And copywriting is simply the
advertising text. In English, copy
means advertising text. And you go to
America and say, I'm a copywriter, everyone
knows what it is. If you're in Italy, DG,
you're a copywaiter, they look at you as if you
were an alien. Okay, it's not an
alien, so what do you mean by copywriter and the person who
writes the ads? Let's use the
usual example that I
always use as an example of an ice cream shop because I
like ice cream, especially the black
cherry one, it's good. Let's say you're
an ice cream shop, okay, and  Linosa, don't worry,
you're selling your ice creams and then
a global pandemic arrives, Covid arrives and
you have to start selling at
home, ok, music, just eat, or
maybe there's your website where you can create a
form that lets people choose the
flavor, the type of ice cream, the
tub, what they can have
your ice cream delivered directly to their home.
The problem is that it's important to
go around your city and
find an ice cream shop. It's one thing to go
looking for an ice cream shop. Or why? It's
completely different because if I search for
an ice cream shop online I can find
thousands, while if I go around my city I
find one or two, maybe trendy ones. Which
means that if I'm an ice cream shop,
then from the point of view of those who
own the ice cream shop and I go online on
Facebook and Instagram on Google, there's a lot
more competition, so there's a lot more
chance that people will choose
another ice cream shop, also because
people don't have to do anything else,
order, which means nothing changes whether
they order from the closest one or the
furthest one, in the end the final result is
the same: they'll have an ice cream in front of
their house. From the
ice cream shop's point of view, it means  that you must have a
better product above all that you must
know how to sell it because because if I go
online there are two ice cream shops A and
BIS. Ice cream shop A has a terrible sale.
I choose ice cream shop B because it has a
better sale. If they present
their products better, they know how
to sell their own better than ice cream shop B has a
better sale because they hired a
copywriter very likely because at 8 so that
the person who wrote the
texts on their site who wrote the
texts on their social networks in a
qualified and prepared person knows how to write
persuasive and convincing texts because
however the copywriter and this and what does he
deal with there are many types
of texts that a copyright could
deal with there are landing pages there are
the description and email marketing
email sequences can be
many types now let's
analyze some of them this one which is better
now on the screen is a
marketing email that I received I found
in my house and some
Gmail promotions this was written by a
copyright what you see now is an ad
or an advertisement that can be
broadcast on Facebook on Instagram
wherever you see this is an image with
some  graphics with drawings with
photos the copywriter and the attention is not
the one who goes to write graphics is not
the one who goes to put the photos north more
rider is only the person who writes the
text the copywriter simply has to
write the text delivers it to the client
will have to write in Word in Google Docs in
[ __ ] open office that I ask for delivery
to the client and then the client goes to make an
email but to use the CRM which are
tools that are not interesting as a
copywriter goes to make the images goes to
make graphics puts them together in an
advertisement now for some people this
is a discussion that it is not always them
companies do it faster to write the texts
themselves now because companies do not
write the copy themselves because they do not
do this email
marketing text this now for leads I remain
for lady ASL which are video sales read
where the sales oil in which
higher co write the script because they do not
do these things themselves these things that to
make copies there are proven strategies there are
techniques you can
use to make it better there are
sales strategies if these strategies did
not exist if they were fantasy a
copywriter 1 would not exist nor would they be
the sellers would not exist
The Wall Street thousand
sales strategies exist, the techniques to sell
more are real and applied in the
right way by the right people,
they help to increase sales, they help to
sell more and make companies make more money,
companies know this thing and that's
why they go to hire
copywriters, okay, from here it should all make
sense, we have a couple more
examples of copies that can be
found, I mentioned dl, they are video sales
letters, video sales letters, the
copyright in this case goes to write
the sales script, a company has
however worked and BRS Business
Solutions, a B to B is very
interesting, the product is a bit
advanced, I'm explaining it to you, but it's an
example of good because I did my ASL,
there are also landing pages which are
very very common, landing pages
often coincide with sales pages but they should
not be confused and landing pages are the
landing pages, that is, the pages
where tours and addresses people if I
tell you guys click the link in b
where the page that is for from the link in
bio is the landing page for where you to
Terry on my site, it from landing page
coincides with the sales page so you are
sort of what it is and the page  sales
or where you can click to buy it
sales page ex always written by a
copywriter and it is one of the most
important things and that generally pays more
in copy because they are
extremely technical and because they are a
bit longer extremely technical
because it is not easy to make sure that
the person can read a nice
big text there are rules to follow
now I am going to explain some
techniques and some copywriting basics
that should allow him to have a
little more perspective on how a copywriter
works what he writes what he does so
remember that the copywriter writes a
text in docs let's talk about the
structure first let's talk about how
this text should be presented first of all the
text must not be like this the text must
be like this appearance is that the second
text is much more schematic and
organized into paragraphs that are
logical blocks which means that they are
logical blocks simply means
that the text is prettier and more
inviting if you see a nice
big text with the same text like a
middle school essay it doesn't encourage you to
read it and people online are not
online to read and
understand ok they are online to
consume content to be
entertained so they will never read it
this but they are much more encouraged
to read something of this kind
we are saying that it is divided into
logical docs which means it unifies that each
paragraph is a logical block therefore it
contains various concepts and be careful the
sentences must be short and each sentence
must contain an idea morally a
paragraph in copywriting is made up of two
and five sentences approximately ok it is a rule
but it rarely goes to this number and
therefore it is three four lines of words
and stuff then you go to a new line you are if it
breaks it is much easier for the reader
to be invited and
much nicer to read another thing
that is very important and is to divide the
headings which in copywriting
are called and ding ding heading and
it is abbreviated with a chi minh city I say h1
h2 h3 simply I am going to indicate the
first the second the third the fourth
heading and so on so if you use many
headings like in this exam it is much
easier for people to go and
read so for example if you are
explaining to me 5 steps to be more attractive
instead of doing a boatload like this in the
meantime on Apple DVD in paragraphs ok bam
bam then my writing  maybe step 1
step 2 step 3 step 4 and so on audi
it will be much easier for the reader
to find what they really want
another thing another reason why
this is very important in the copy and
why people want to go and
find the information they are looking for sub
if they don't find the information they
are looking for immediately they go away it must be
clear with the section in which you go to
explain that information
specifically so to summarize we were
talking about a schematic text a text
that is written in a way that is easy to
read and that invites reading
another thing that clearly invites reading
are the images you can
suggest to the client to insert
images for example at a certain point
in your text write in brackets
insert here an image of a
smiling child insert here an image of an
ice cream in the case of the ice cream shop and so
on ok next thing about copywriting and
here we go a bit about selling and it is one
of the most important concepts of
selling in general ok and it is the reason
why people buy if you want to
sell to people in the meantime you have to understand
who he is against selling me something
ok in I would go to understand why I am
led to buy what it is that convinces
people to buy what it is that  Athena,
this desire to buy, to spend
money, then the first thing you have to
understand is that no one buys a
product that doesn't solve a problem.
Every product, everything you buy in
this world, every single thing solves
a problem. There are two types of
problems: problems that money
solves a pain. Problems that, when
solved, give me pleasure. For
example, buying ice cream,
buying Gucci, buying
Versace, going to watch a movie.
These are all pleasures. Okay, a watch,
a nice house, a swimming pool, etc. A
problem, however, generally can be
anything else, like
physical pain, so medicines, a
physical problem like vision, so
glasses solve that problem. The
problem, for example, is money. I'm
telling you, it's the investment with my company.
Why do
you want money? You have a problem. You need money.
I'll help you solve this
problem. Okay, so as you see, every
product in this world, from me, I
can give you a problem. You know,
how can this
information help you? What does it change for you? I'll say
that when you're trying to bender, you
as a copywriter are trying to sell
a product, you have to exploit
this problem, you have to leverage this problem.
In copywriting it's called pain point, okay,
the problem that is solved and the time
in quotation marks is pain point. What
the copyright does is literally
press on that pain, like
studying Messina, finished, I'll stop above
to make it hurt even more. We
use these persuasion strategies
to get to convince and
make the person understand that that problem,
that pain, needs to be solved. To solve it, you
need our product. You're hungry, okay? I'll
make you understand that you're hungry, that if you don't
eat, you'll starve to death. And Randy. My
follow-up request is a very
banal example that should make you understand how
this works. It works very, very,
very well when you have to solve a
problem, not to achieve a pleasure.
In the case of pleasure, there are other
strategies that are very similar
to the ones I'm explaining to you. It's probably
because you need this concept of
problem. Where do you use this problem?
Then there's a structure to
follow in copywriting. Okay, the structure is the
following. First, you have to reach
people, so if it's not
people's attention and people don't
listen to you, then step number 1:
attention, reach the 3 or 2 problem,
so you have to go and explain this
problem. Now someone might ask me, I would
go, but they  they know their problem
is that I have to explain it and instead you
have to explain it to them not so much because they don't
know it even if it could be that they
are not aware of how
serious that problem is but simply
because if you explain the problem to them
almost better than they can
explain it to themselves then they
will understand that you really understand
their situation and I am a person who
understands their situation can help
these people solve it or if you don't
understand my investment problem
how do you solve them and file access
can't in Setubal sell me is that
thing your solution
investment consultancy let me understand and the more you
understand what my problem is second
step explain the problem problem there would
be two other intermediate steps
now I'm not going to explain it to you because
we are extremely long in the course
I go very very very very and therefore details
also on these other steps but let's go
to the end city and the sites and the call to
action call to action so when
you go to say the customer or in the second
so as you can see it is very intuitive and a
very interesting game
and so fun indeed really
fun to use these problems the
point is that when you have a
new product what it has to do it has to go  to do
research so if you don't know
that industry that product to sell
to do the necessary research in the course
teaches how to do this research to
make find the information you
need on that industry on the
white one we are I want to explain a
couple more concepts to you before leaving ok
so at least you have some more things xenon
bonus compared to what I wanted to say
we have pain amplification regency
amplification then I d yes amplifies
that is to amplify the urgency the urgency
what is the urgency and the portion of people
to buy the certain thing you want to make
sure that people buy now
and not in 5 months or that they continue to
postpone the purchase because people
human beings in class one by
nature you have to use the energy
amplification if instead you want to amplify
the pain and that yesterday pressing on the
wound uses network in amplification true
amplify the pain so that to make
these people understand that they must
necessarily solve the problem
they have now and to solve it they must
buy the product ok so these
are two other two concepts that
will be very this was the video I think it was
very useful if you are
interested in understanding much more about
copyright in so go to the  Details
on each step, go on, details on
objections, which are another step that he didn't
explain to us, on the tests needed
to manage them, on the strategies
to amplify the urgency, to
amplify the pain, on the
research strategies and above all how to find
clients and how to start earning
money as an online copywriter on your computer
wherever you are in the world. Go and buy
the copywriting course. Right now,
the course costs 249 euros,
but starting September 15th, so in just
over twenty days. In just
over 20 days, the course will increase in price
to 690 euros, so that's a big difference
in price. I recommend you buy it
now, at least you'll save a lot of
money on the cost. I
remind you that once you've completed the course, there are
n't just video lessons
that explain how to do it, there's
extra content such as downloadable PDFs,
product exercises to practice on,
access to the Telegram group where
we only exchange information on
bodies, no [ __ ], nothing for you. You have
time, advice on copywriting, costs, on
clients, consent to these things and especially, it
will also be the possibility of having a
video call with me where you can go.
This is completely optional,
only if you want.  Let's
discuss problems that you may encounter
during your journey, so maybe you ca
n't find clients, maybe you can't
write a good copy, or even you
can't raise the prices of your services
to earn even more. I
will help you solve all these
problems, so I recommend you
click the link in bio. In India's bio,
you will find all the information about the course,
what it contains, and the mind to
purchase, it's all in there. So for
info or to purchase, linking bio,
we'll meet there. She's a beautiful girl,
bye.